hey everybody welcome to this a1
english listening practice video you can
use this video
to practice your listening and
comprehension
as i speak before we start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready
so today i'm gonna talk about education
this is an essential topic because
education is an important part of our
lives
most people get some kind of education
education is different in different
countries
but today we'll talk about education
in the u.s so first let's talk about the
different
levels of education in the u.s
the first level of education is
preschool
in the u.s kids go to preschool
when they're four years old but not
everyone goes to preschool some people
don't go i went to preschool when i was
four
i didn't like it because i was very shy
i didn't like playing with other kids
when i was young in preschool children
play a lot but they also learn
after preschool children go to
kindergarten
usually kids start kindergarten when
they're
5 years old in kindergarten children
start learning more things for example
they learn to read write and make art
they also learn how to be good students
i remember that when i was in
kindergarten
we had discipline if we did something
bad
we got in trouble i never got in trouble
because i was a good student so
after kindergarten you go to elementary
school
in the u.s most elementary schools
include 1st second third
fourth fifth and sixth grade
but some elementary schools don't
include
sixth grade in each year of elementary
school
you only have one teacher you have
the same teacher all year in my opinion
elementary school isn't that difficult
in the us of course you get homework
but it's not too much in elementary
school
you learn many things like math
science history and english
at this level you spend about 6 hours
at school then after elementary school
you go to middle school or junior high
i say middle school but both of these
names
are correct middle school usually
includes
7th and 8th grade at this level
students have many teachers like six
or seven i had six different classes
each year in middle school each class
was one hour long i didn't like middle
school
it's much harder than elementary school
you get more homework and you have more
tests
then after middle school you go to high
school
in the u.s high school includes 9th
10th 11th and 12th grade
this is the most important time for
students
in the u.s if you want to go to college
then it's important to do well in high
school
high school can be difficult but it
depends on your teachers
some teachers give a lot of homework and
some teachers
don't and some teachers are good at
teaching
and some teachers aren't i had some good
teachers in high school
but i also had some bad teachers
so after high school some people go to
college
and some people don't of course there
are
different levels of university and you
can
earn different degrees there okay
so lastly let's look at a few important
vocabulary words
related to education first let's talk
about the word
grades we use the word grades
to talk about how well you did in a
class
or on a test in the us
these grades are a b
c d and f an a
grade is the best and an f
grade is the worst okay the next word
is recess in the u.s
recess is the short break that
elementary school students have during
their school day
during recess students play
talk or eat a snack this break
is usually 20 or 30 minutes
okay the last phrase you should learn is
bachelor's degree a bachelor's degree
is the degree you get after four years
of university it's lower than a master's
degree
alright that's all for today leave a
comment
and tell me about your education and
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram for more
english tips and lessons i'll see you
next time
[Music]